<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MainStruct – Chapter 2 · Point Structure</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 2 · Point Structure on MainStruct</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is a Point Structure</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/what-is-point/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/what-is-point/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;2.1 What Is a Point Structure&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;21-what-is-a-point-structure&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#21-what-is-a-point-structure&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the earliest state of human cognition, nothing has yet been distinguished.&lt;br&gt;
At this stage, what we face is not “Object A” or “Object B,” but a vague and undivided whole.&lt;br&gt;
We have not yet cut it apart, nor assigned it meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;undifferentiated state&lt;/strong&gt; is what we call the &lt;strong&gt;point structure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point structure has several core features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indistinction&lt;/strong&gt;: Within the point structure, there is no division between “good” and “bad,” or “inside” and “outside.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlabeled&lt;/strong&gt;: Things have not yet been named, so no judgment exists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potentiality&lt;/strong&gt;: It is not emptiness, but a starting point that can split into distinctions at any moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;br&gt;
A newborn opening their eyes for the first time does not immediately distinguish “this is my mother’s face, this is the wall.” In their perception, all input is still an undivided whole. Only with accumulated experience do boundaries like “person” and “object” begin to emerge on top of the point structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the perspective of structural language, the point structure is the &lt;strong&gt;zero-dimensional unit cell of cognition&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
It does not represent any concrete state, but rather marks the &lt;strong&gt;starting point of all judgment and differentiation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The significance of understanding the point structure is this:&lt;br&gt;
All subsequent structures (line structures, surface structures, volumetric structures) must grow from here. If we do not acknowledge the existence of the point structure, we cannot explain &lt;strong&gt;why the same external stimulus generates completely different judgments in different individuals&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, the point structure is:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The original stage of subjective cognition—the source of all structures.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subjective Intention in the Point Structure</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/subjective-intent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/subjective-intent/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;2.2 Subjective Intention in the Point Structure&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;22-subjective-intention-in-the-point-structure&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#22-subjective-intention-in-the-point-structure&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the point structure is an “undifferentiated” whole, it is not a passive blank.&lt;br&gt;
Within every individual’s cognition, the point structure is always accompanied by an initial driving force—&lt;strong&gt;subjective intention&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key features of subjective intention:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Precedes judgment&lt;/strong&gt;: Intention exists before we begin to divide things into “yes/no” or “good/bad.”&lt;br&gt;
For example, when you feel hunger, all perceptions are oriented toward the distinction of “edible or not,” rather than unfolding at random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Filters perception&lt;/strong&gt;: Intention determines which line you cut out of the point structure.&lt;br&gt;
In a meeting, if you come with the intention of “proving yourself,” you will be more sensitive to signs of doubt or rejection.&lt;br&gt;
If you come with the intention of “collaboration,” you will more easily notice support and opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generates direction&lt;/strong&gt;: The point structure itself has no inherent meaning; meaning is assigned by intention.&lt;br&gt;
Intention acts like the first stroke of a brush on a blank canvas, initiating differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the point structure is never “static.” It is always in a state of potential activation by intention.&lt;br&gt;
The same external stimulus may be split into completely different structures depending on the underlying intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A red light at an intersection means “obstruction” to someone in a hurry, but “an opportunity to rest” to someone tired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The same facial expression may signal “caring” to a lover, but “provocation” to a competitor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intention decides how the point structure fractures.&lt;br&gt;
It is the first driving force that carries us from an &lt;strong&gt;undifferentiated whole&lt;/strong&gt; into the &lt;strong&gt;structured world&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words:&lt;br&gt;
Without subjective intention, there is no structure.&lt;br&gt;
The point structure and subjective intention are an inseparable starting pair in human cognition.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point Structure and the Origins of Cognition</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/cognition-origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter2-point/cognition-origin/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;2.3 Point Structure and the Origins of Cognition&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;23-point-structure-and-the-origins-of-cognition&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#23-point-structure-and-the-origins-of-cognition&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from the relationship between point structure and subjective intention, we can trace the very origins of human cognition.&lt;br&gt;
All complex judgments and reasoning ultimately return to the initial state:&lt;br&gt;
an undifferentiated whole, split by some intention into the first distinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The infant example&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-infant-example&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-infant-example&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a newborn, the world is a blurred whole, without clear separations such as “cup,” “mother,” or “sound.”&lt;br&gt;
But when the intention of &lt;em&gt;hunger&lt;/em&gt; arises, the infant picks out the smell of milk and the mother’s chest.&lt;br&gt;
When the intention of &lt;em&gt;safety&lt;/em&gt; arises, the infant captures the embrace and the rhythm of a heartbeat.&lt;br&gt;
The world itself has not changed, but within the infant’s point structure, intention shapes the first cut of differentiation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The evolution of cognition&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-evolution-of-cognition&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-evolution-of-cognition&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As humans grow, they continuously carve new distinctions from the point structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From “edible / not edible” to “like / dislike.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From “safe / dangerous” to “respect / insult.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From “cooperation / conflict” to “justice / evil.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these higher-level judgments are layered on top of the original fracture within the point structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fundamental insight&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;fundamental-insight&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#fundamental-insight&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structure is not fixed externally&lt;/strong&gt;: it is not a set of labels carried by objective things, but a product of cognition driven by intention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognition originates from intention&lt;/strong&gt;: without intention, there is no distinction; without distinction, there is no structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Point structure is the foundation&lt;/strong&gt;: any complex social negotiation, cultural system, or worldview can ultimately be reduced to a single cut made on a point structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, to understand the point structure is to understand the origin of cognition.&lt;br&gt;
It reveals that the so-called “world” is not simply lying there passively—it is continuously being sliced and constructed by intention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words:&lt;br&gt;
The world does not &lt;em&gt;already&lt;/em&gt; have meaning, waiting for us to discover it.&lt;br&gt;
Rather, we first have intention, and then we assign meaning to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
