<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MainStruct – Chapter 1 · Introduction</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 1 · Introduction on MainStruct</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do We Need a New Language?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/why-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/why-language/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;1.1 Why Invent a Language for Human Behavior&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;11-why-invent-a-language-for-human-behavior&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#11-why-invent-a-language-for-human-behavior&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day, we deal with people: conflicts at home, games in the workplace, and the subtle atmosphere of social settings.&lt;br&gt;
These interactions often feel vague, complex, and even inexplicable. The same sentence can trigger completely opposite reactions in different listeners; the same situation can carry entirely different meanings depending on who is looking at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem lies in this: &lt;strong&gt;we lack a language that can precisely describe human behavior.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Existing natural languages are mostly narrative, filled with emotion and ambiguity. Psychology and sociology provide concepts, but they rarely form reusable or computable expressions. Scientific methods emphasize evidence, but often ignore subjective intentions and contextual differences. As a result, we are left using words like “it feels like,” “sort of,” or “probably” to describe the logic behind behavior—without ever making it truly clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates a universal dilemma:&lt;br&gt;
We can sense structures, but we cannot express them. We know there are patterns between people, but we cannot convert them into computable expressions. Without language, we lack tools. Without tools, every conflict or collaboration must start from scratch, relying only on intuition and experience—without systematic ways to learn and improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we need a new linguistic system: &lt;strong&gt;structural language&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
It does not replace natural language, but supplements it—helping us describe human intentions, relationships, and interactions with greater precision. Such a language must satisfy a few basic conditions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Centered on the “I”&lt;/strong&gt;: All judgments originate from subjective stance, not from the illusion of “objective omniscience.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decomposable and composable&lt;/strong&gt;: Complex relationships must be breakable into minimal structural units that can then be recombined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verifiable and transferable&lt;/strong&gt;: The same expressions must work across different contexts—whether analyzing family, workplace, politics, or social systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, this is not just a new “theory” for academia, but a &lt;strong&gt;cognitive tool&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
Just as mathematics allows us to calculate quantity, and music allows us to express emotion, structural language will allow us to capture and express the precise forms of &lt;strong&gt;human behavioral patterns&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Perspective and Subjective Stance</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/subjective-stance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/subjective-stance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;1.2 Structural Perspective and Subjective Stance&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;12-structural-perspective-and-subjective-stance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#12-structural-perspective-and-subjective-stance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In traditional cognition, we are accustomed to pursuing the so-called “objective truth.”&lt;br&gt;
However, no human judgment can ever fully escape its own circumstances.&lt;br&gt;
Every judgment begins from the stance of “I.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the same meeting, the boss may feel that employees are passive, while employees may feel the boss is aggressive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a relationship, one person may see “care,” while the other sees “control.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a negotiation, the buyer may feel it’s a “good deal,” while the seller feels “pressured.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The facts have not changed, but different stances lead to entirely different interpretations and meanings.&lt;br&gt;
This shows: structure is not an inherent property of the external world, but a cognitive product activated by stance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, structural language must make clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start from the subjective&lt;/strong&gt; — every structural analysis must first mark “whose perspective” it represents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distinguish intention from appearance&lt;/strong&gt; — the meaning of behavior depends on subjective intention, not external display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledge multiple versions&lt;/strong&gt; — the same event, seen from different roles, will generate different structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stance-based way of expression is not a denial of the objective existence of the world, but an emphasis that:&lt;br&gt;
what we can access is always reality refracted through subjectivity.&lt;br&gt;
If we fail to recognize this, every discussion of human behavior will fall into confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of structural language lies precisely here:&lt;br&gt;
it enables us, in complex interpersonal and social relations, to clearly distinguish and present different subjective perspectives in parallel—&lt;br&gt;
instead of being forced into the illusion of a single “objective truth.”&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Prospects of Structural Language</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/applications/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;1.3 The Prospects of Structural Language&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;13-the-prospects-of-structural-language&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#13-the-prospects-of-structural-language&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Sections 1.1 and 1.2 explained why a new language is needed, and why it must be grounded in subjective stance,&lt;br&gt;
then the next question is: &lt;strong&gt;What can it be used for?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Individual Level&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;1-individual-level&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-individual-level&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding relationships&lt;/strong&gt;: With structural language, people can more quickly identify the “misalignment of intentions” behind conflicts, avoiding emotional disputes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-reflection&lt;/strong&gt;: By expressing situations through structural units, one can clearly see their own stance, motives, and possible biases in a matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decision optimization&lt;/strong&gt;: Converting vague feelings into structural expressions often reveals new paths of choice—beyond the binary trap of “either this or that.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Organizational and Societal Level&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;2-organizational-and-societal-level&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#2-organizational-and-societal-level&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management and collaboration&lt;/strong&gt;: Team conflicts often stem from inconsistent structural perspectives among members. Structural language makes such differences explicit, enabling higher-level coordination.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Negotiation and game-playing&lt;/strong&gt;: In business, diplomacy, and legal negotiations, the ability to grasp the other party’s subjective stance often determines the outcome. Structural language provides a transferable method of analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Education and training&lt;/strong&gt;: Structural expression can serve as a universal training tool, helping people systematically learn “how to understand others’ stances.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Technology and Future Level&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;3-technology-and-future-level&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#3-technology-and-future-level&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;: Current AI lacks a structural understanding of “subjective intention” when processing human language. Introducing structural language can give AI a more human-like mode of judgment in interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge management&lt;/strong&gt;: With structural expression, fragmented experiences can be transformed into searchable, transferable case libraries that support future decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social system design&lt;/strong&gt;: On a larger scale, structural language has the potential to become a new tool of social science—describing group behavior, institutional games, and cultural differences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the significance of structural language lies not only in “seeing clearly,” but also in “being actionable.”&lt;br&gt;
It is not a doctrine that remains in abstract concepts, but a cognitive tool ready to be applied to solve problems.&lt;br&gt;
In the future—whether in personal growth, organizational operation, or technological development—its applications will be indispensable.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
