<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MainStruct – Subjectivity</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/en/tags/subjectivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Subjectivity on MainStruct</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/en/tags/subjectivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Perspective and Subjective Stance</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/subjective-stance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/en/docs/chapter1-intro/subjective-stance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2&gt;1.2 Structural Perspective and Subjective Stance&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;12-structural-perspective-and-subjective-stance&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#12-structural-perspective-and-subjective-stance&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In traditional cognition, we are accustomed to pursuing the so-called “objective truth.”&lt;br&gt;
However, no human judgment can ever fully escape its own circumstances.&lt;br&gt;
Every judgment begins from the stance of “I.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the same meeting, the boss may feel that employees are passive, while employees may feel the boss is aggressive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a relationship, one person may see “care,” while the other sees “control.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a negotiation, the buyer may feel it’s a “good deal,” while the seller feels “pressured.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The facts have not changed, but different stances lead to entirely different interpretations and meanings.&lt;br&gt;
This shows: structure is not an inherent property of the external world, but a cognitive product activated by stance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, structural language must make clear:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start from the subjective&lt;/strong&gt; — every structural analysis must first mark “whose perspective” it represents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distinguish intention from appearance&lt;/strong&gt; — the meaning of behavior depends on subjective intention, not external display.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledge multiple versions&lt;/strong&gt; — the same event, seen from different roles, will generate different structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This stance-based way of expression is not a denial of the objective existence of the world, but an emphasis that:&lt;br&gt;
what we can access is always reality refracted through subjectivity.&lt;br&gt;
If we fail to recognize this, every discussion of human behavior will fall into confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value of structural language lies precisely here:&lt;br&gt;
it enables us, in complex interpersonal and social relations, to clearly distinguish and present different subjective perspectives in parallel—&lt;br&gt;
instead of being forced into the illusion of a single “objective truth.”&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
